Speaker: How to survive coming to study in the UK
You have a place to study in the UK, you have your visa, and you’ve found accommodation,
and you’re ready to go.
You’re very excited – but you also have so many questions!
But don’t worry.
This guide, compiled with the help of many international students,
aims to help make your first year at university
or college everything that you have always hoped for.
Here are four important tips:
1 Pack intelligently before you come.
It’s never too early to start packing! Make sure you bring these things:
Suitable clothes.
The UK may be colder and wetter than your country,
so bring warm clothes and a raincoat!
Adaptors.
You can of course buy these in the UK,
but you will probably want to use your laptop and phone immediately.
Kitchen equipment.
If you’re planning to cook some of your meals,
pack some essential cooking equipment so you can start cooking from day one.
2 Get to know your city.
Before you come, have a good look online at the area
where you’re going to live, for example, on Google Street View.
Then check all the places you would like to visit in your new city.
There are lots of ways of making city travel cheaper, like the Oyster card in London.
You can also get a discount at many places like museums or cinemas with your student ID card.
3 Learn to manage your money.
You may find you have a lot of money in your bank account at the beginning of term,
but after a few weeks, it’s all gone!
Try to make a spending plan and stick to it.
Many students get part-time jobs, for example, in a bar or café, or sometimes on campus.
Jobs are also good to put on your CV,
and are good work experience, too.
4 Make friends.
It can be a bit frightening to come to a new country on your own.
But don’t worry, there are many ways to make friends.
All universities have lots of clubs for all kinds of free-time activities
like sports, games, music, and other more unusual things.
You can find out about them in the first week of term,
usually called Fresher’s Week.
If you’re a bit homesick, almost all cultures have their own societies which organize events,
so you can meet other students from your country.
So those are four tips for how to survive coming to study in the UK.
Good luck, and have a great time!